JONATHAN WEBER

UI/UX DESIGNER & **DEVELOPER**

(760) 419-0734



□ Jonweber09@gmail.com



Vista, CA



🥏 https://jonweberportfol.io



in Jonweber09



JayWebz

9+ years experienced, dynamic, and diligent Web UI/UX Designer and Developer with an exemplary history of researching, designing, building, updating, and managing websites and web applications using objectoriented best practices, usercentric design, and modern programming tools and languages. Well-versed in taking Single-Page Applications from ideation to launch, using CMS', connecting APIs to Web Uls, and creating data-heavy visualizations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web tech & frameworks - HTML5, CSS3, ReactJS, Redux Scripting - JavaScript, Node.js, PHP, Python Debug: Chrome, Firefox Application/Web Server: Apache (XAMPP), Webpack, Symfony Versioning/Other tools: Git,

Mercurial, JIRA, Beanstalk, Sourcetree, Postman Deployment Tools: Jenkins, Docker, Surge, Git Deploy

MANAGERIAL SKILLS

Front-end Development Agile Method Code Optimization **UI** Enhancement Stakeholder Management **Documentation & Reporting**

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Center for Applied Internet Data Analysis 11/2019 - PRESENT » UI/UX Designer & Developer

- > Designed and Developed two data-driven applications from ideation to launch, one that detects macroscopic internet outages in near-realtime and one that serves as a resource catalog to help search and filter through research assets.
- > Created UI Information Architecture based on stakeholder feedback, developing user personas, and google analytics insight using OmniGraffle diagramming tool to visualize content hierarchy and relationships.
- > Built navigable low-fidelity prototype for basic functionality and layout of each template page using Axure UX software.
- > Designed high-fidelity mockups for colors, design, and feel of each template page.
- > Developed front-end UI with tools for data visualization and exploration related to network monitoring/measurements.
- > Managed post-deployment interviews and user-research to help design next iterations and future feature planing.

NTN Buzztime, Inc. » Web Developer

09/2013 - PRESENT 12/2016 - PRESENT

- > Develop UI/UX across several single-page applications and websites while managing the data interchange between servers and users using RESTful/SOAP API calls via http requests.
- > Utilize ReactJS including creating forms, managing events, building dynamic reusable components, generating data-driven geolocation maps, and integrating redux for smart components.

» Digital Marketing Manager

08/2015 - 11/2016

- > Developed the front-end of primary website through WordPress CMS with Software Engineer and increased incoming qualified leads by 40% over a four month period.
- > Designed and optimized online marketing & advertising campaigns via search marketing, email, and social media.

» Digital Marketing Coordinator

09/2013 - 08/2015

- > Designed responsive landing pages, email templates, banners, and other graphics for use in digital promotions and lead-generation.
- > Managed development schedule to optimize deliverability metrics through enterprise-level Marketing automation software.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

South Coast Surety

01/2018 - 11/2018

- > Designed and developed template-based Wordpress website working with backend developer.
 - > ENV: Wordpress/PHP, HTML, Sass, NPM

EDUCATION

Mira Costa College

01/2014 - 12/2017

> Programming with Python

- > Web Design: PHP/Wordpress
- → E-Commerce & Web Presence → Mobile Sites & Apps
- > Site Design & Architecture
- JavaScript and ¡Query

CSU, San Marcos

08/2007 - 05/2012

> B.S. Business Administration - Global Business Management and Marketing, Minor German Language